Yumi
유미
Yumi's Cells
유미의 세포
Episode 21 : The Great Encyclopedia of Yumi
21화 : 유미대백과사전
40 years later
40년 후
Welcome everyone. This is the Yumi Great Library.
모두를 환영합니다. 이곳은 유미대도서관입니다.
Here.
여기.
This is a historic place which contains all the information about Yumi.
이곳은 유미에 관한 모든 정보가 담겨 있는 역사적인 장소입니다.
All right, this way.
알았어, 이쪽으로.
Yes, ma'am!
네, 부인!
We keep photos of Yumi's important events like this.
이렇게 유미의 중요한 행사 사진을 보관하고 있습니다.
Wow, there is a wedding picture here also!
와, 여기도 웨딩 사진이 있군요!
Really?
정말?
Please come this way, everyone.
여러분, 이쪽으로 오세요.
Yes, ma'am.
네, 부인.
Now, these books are the great encyclopedias of Yumi.
이제 이 책들은 유미의 위대한 백과사전이다.
One book is published each year and there are currently 72 volumes,
매년 한 권씩 출간되며 현재 72권으로 구성되어 있습니다.
because our Yumi has turned seventy-two years old.
우리 유미가 일흔두 살이 되었기 때문이죠.
Everything about Yumi is recorded here.
유미에 관한 모든 것이 여기에 기록됩니다.
Do you have any questions?
질문이 있으신가요?
Me! I'd like to know what was the first award that Yumi got.
나! 유미가 받은 첫 상이 무엇인지 알고 싶습니다.
The first award?
첫 번째 수상?
That is probably...
아마도...
in the seventh volume.
일곱 번째 권에서.
Here we go.
여기 있습니다.
The first ever award that Yumi got was...
유미가 처음으로 받은 상은...
This award is for participating in the children's art competition.
이 상은 어린이 미술 대회에 참가한 데 대한 상입니다.
Good job, Yumi.
잘했어, 유미.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
It was a participation award for an art competition.
미술대회 참가상이었습니다.
Award
수상
For your information, Yumi never won another award at an art competition ever since.
참고로 유미는 그 이후로 미술대회에서 또 한 번도 상을 받은 적이 없습니다.
Any other questions?
다른 질문이 있나요?
Ma'am, what was the most embarrassing moment in Yumi's life?
부인, 유미의 인생에서 가장 창피했던 순간은 언제였나요?
That's a good question. There were three most embarrassing incidents in Yumi's life.
좋은 질문이네요. 유미의 인생에는 세 가지 가장 당황스러운 사건이 있었습니다.
The best out of them...
그 중 최고는...
happened in the summer when she was 32 years old.
그녀가 32세였던 여름에 일어난 일이다.
I'll take the picture now. Look at the camera. One, two, three.
지금 사진을 찍겠습니다. 카메라를보세요. 하나 둘 셋.
Incident name, Hong Na Ri Wedding Incident. [Hong Na Ri Wedding Incident, August 15th]
사건명, 홍나리 결혼식 사건. [홍나리 결혼식 사건, 8월 15일]
- I'm getting married in the spring. March. - With that woman?
- 올 봄에 결혼해요. 3월. - 그 여자랑요?
Incident summary. When she heard that her ex-boyfriend Ji Wu Gi, whom she ran into at her friend Hong Na Ri's wedding,
사건 요약. 친구 홍나리의 결혼식에서 우연히 만난 전 남자친구 지우기의 소식을 듣고
was getting married,
결혼했어요
What the hell is that crazy bastard saying?
저 미친놈이 대체 무슨 소리를 하는 거지?
Sensitivity got shocked and went nuts.
감도는 충격을 받고 미쳐갔습니다.
Actually, I'm getting married soon, too.
사실 저도 곧 결혼해요.
- Really? - Yes. I think I'll do it next year as well.
- 정말? - 예. 내년에도 할 것 같아요.
But you'll probably be first. It hasn't been long since I was proposed to.
하지만 아마 당신이 첫 번째일 거예요. 프러포즈를 받은 지 얼마 안 됐어요.
Oh, I forgot my ring. Actually, we're planning on going abroad to have a small wedding.
아, 반지를 깜빡했어요. 사실 저희는 해외로 가서 스몰웨딩을 할 계획이에요.
We're thinking about Hawaii for the location.
우리는 위치를 하와이로 생각하고 있습니다.
After she lied like crazy,
그녀가 미친 듯이 거짓말을 한 후
Congratulations.
축하해요.
she got caught by Gu Wung, her boyfriend at that time.
당시 남자친구였던 구웅에게 붙잡혔다.
Wow, so embarrassing!
와, 너무 창피해요!
I never thought Yumi would have such a dark past.
유미가 이렇게 어두운 과거를 가지고 있을 거라고는 상상도 못했어요.
Ma'am, so what happened?
부인, 그래서 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
And I'd like to congratulate you.
그리고 축하드리고 싶습니다.
- For what? - I heard you're getting married soon.
- 무엇 때문에요? - 곧 결혼하신다고 들었어요.
Oh.
오.
I just heard that you're getting married next year.
내년에 결혼하신다는 소식을 방금 들었어요.
Yes, that's right.
네, 맞습니다.
Yes, thank you.
네, 감사합니다.
Yumi, let's go in. I think the ceremony started.
유미야, 들어가자. 결혼식이 시작된 것 같아.
Which island in Hawaii are you having it at?
하와이 어느 섬에서 드시나요?
I'm thinking about doing a small wedding abroad as well.
해외에서도 스몰웨딩을 해볼 생각이에요.
I envy you. Which island are you thinking about having it at?
나는 당신이 부러워요. 어느 섬에서 드실 생각이신가요?
- Sorry? - It's the Hawaii island.
- 죄송합니다? - 하와이 섬이에요.
So which one in Hawaii?
그럼 하와이에는 어느 곳이 있나요?
There are four main islands in Hawaii.
하와이에는 4개의 주요 섬이 있습니다.
You said you're having it in Hawaii.
하와이에서 드신다고 하셨어요.
Right...
그렇죠...
Of course we want to have it in Hawaii.
물론 우리는 그것을 하와이에서 갖고 싶습니다.
That's why we're contemplating which one we should pick.
그렇기 때문에 우리는 어느 쪽을 선택해야 할지 고민하고 있습니다.
Which company did you contact? I'm thinking about it too, so can you share with me?
어느 회사에 연락하셨나요? 저도 고민 중인데 공유해주실 수 있나요?
But we're running late, so we should head inside.
하지만 우리는 시간이 늦어서 안으로 들어가야 해요.
- Right. - I'll let you know later at the reception. - Sure.
- 오른쪽. - 나중에 리셉션에서 알려드리겠습니다. - 확신하는.
Yumi, let's go.
유미, 가자.
You know... you were surprised, right?
있잖아... 놀랐지?
So what happened was that he kept saying weird things. He's crazy.
그래서 그 사람이 계속 이상한 말을 하더군요. 그는 미쳤다.
He kept saying nonsense so I couldn't just not say anything. So Wung—
그 사람이 계속 말도 안 되는 소리를 해서 나는 아무 말도 하지 않을 수가 없었어요. 소 웅—
Was that him? The one you dated for seven years then broke up because he cheated on you.
그 사람이었어? 당신이 7년 동안 사귄 사람은 당신을 속였다는 이유로 헤어졌습니다.
It must be that jerk.
그 바보임에 틀림없어요.
I thought so.
나는 그렇게 생각했다.
He said that he's getting married and that he hoped I won't be hurt.
결혼을 한다고 했고, 제가 상처받지 않았으면 좋겠다고 하더군요.
He was saying that nonsense and I didn't realize...
그 사람이 말도 안 되는 소리를 하고 있었는데 나는 몰랐어요...
Let's go in.
들어가자.
Dearest brothers and sisters,
사랑하는 형제자매 여러분,
to the servants of the Lord who married in the name of Christ...
그리스도의 이름으로 결혼한 주의 종들에게...
Yumi, your boyfriend is so cool!
유미야, 네 남자친구는 정말 멋있어!
Hey, his style was nice.
아, 그 사람 스타일이 좋았어요.
He's so much better than Ji Wu Gi. You got a great one after the trash.
그는 Ji Wu Gi보다 훨씬 낫습니다. 당신은 쓰레기 이후에 훌륭한 것을 얻었습니다.
He's not that great.
그는 그다지 훌륭하지 않습니다.
He was nice. He's so much better than in the picture.
그는 친절했어요. 그 사람은 사진보다 훨씬 나아요.
He created everything with His omnipotent power...
그는 전능하신 능력으로 모든 것을 창조하셨다...
I looked it up and there really are four main islands in Hawaii. Shocking.
검색해 보니 하와이에는 정말 4개의 주요 섬이 있습니다. 충격적인.
Kaua'i, Maui, Oahu, and Big Island.
카우아이, 마우이, 오아후, 빅아일랜드.
I'm furiously memorizing just in case that guy talks to me again.
그 사람이 또 나한테 말을 걸까 봐 맹렬히 외우고 있다.
Do you like Hawaii?
하와이를 좋아하시나요?
No, I've never been there.
아니요, 저는 거기 가본 적이 없습니다.
So why Hawaii?
그렇다면 왜 하와이인가?
I don't know. It just came out.
모르겠습니다. 방금 나왔습니다.
I suddenly want to visit Hawaii.
갑자기 하와이에 가보고 싶어요.
Fortunately, the incident was wrapped up well, thanks to Wung being considerate.
다행히 웡의 배려 덕분에 사건은 잘 마무리됐다.
That's a relief.
다행이네요.
But it wasn't wrapped up all the way.
그러나 그것은 끝까지 마무리되지 않았습니다.
Because there was an aftermath.
후유증이 있었으니까요.
- An aftermath? - Yes, an aftermath.
- 여파? - 응, 여파야.
The Hong Na Ri Wedding Incident didn't just end as an embarrassing event.
The Hong Na Ri Wedding Incident didn't just end as an embarrassing event.
Hyeong, are you marrying Seonbae Yumi?
형, 선배 유미랑 결혼해요?
- What? - A friend of mine is Yumi's school hubae,
- 무엇? - 내 친구는 유미네 학교 후배인데,
and he said that there's a rumor among the alumni that she's marrying you next year.
그리고 동창들 사이에서 그녀가 내년에 당신과 결혼할 것이라는 소문이 돌고 있다고 하더군요.
I heard everything's planned already, too. You're doing a small wedding abroad.
나도 이미 다 계획됐다고 들었어. 해외에서 스몰웨딩을 하고 계시네요.
- Is that true? - Uhhhhh...
- 그게 사실인가요? - 어어어...
What do you mean uhhh?
무슨 말이에요?
Is that true or not?
그게 사실인가요, 아닌가?
If it's true, I'm in favor of this marriage.
그것이 사실이라면 나는 이 결혼에 찬성한다.
I won't comment.
나는 논평하지 않을 것이다.
What the heck? You're making me curious.
도대체 뭐야? 당신은 나를 궁금하게 만들고 있습니다.
Ask Yumi, then.
그럼 유미에게 물어보세요.
Huh? So you're not denying it.
뭐? 그래서 당신은 그것을 부정하지 않습니다.
I said no comment.
나는 아무 말도하지 않았다.
Have you been to Hawaii? There are four main islands in Hawaii.
하와이에 가본 적이 있나요? 하와이에는 4개의 주요 섬이 있습니다.
Wow, you're serious.
와, 진심이군요.
Yumi, congratulations! I heard you were getting married?
유미님, 축하해요! 결혼한다고 들었어?
Yumi! Congrats on your wedding. Rumor has it that your boyfriend is really handsome.
유미! 결혼을 축하합니다. 네 남자친구가 정말 잘생겼다는 소문이 있어.
I heard you're having the wedding in Hawaii. I'm so envious.
하와이에서 결혼식을 올린다고 들었어요. 너무 부럽다.
But guys... I think you misunderstood the rumors.
그런데 여러분... 소문을 오해하신 것 같아요.
I don't know when we will have it.
언제 우리가 그것을 갖게 될지 모르겠습니다.
I heard it's going to be next spring.
내년 봄이 된다고 들었습니다.
No, I was saying that it might be the case
아니, 그럴 수도 있겠다는 뜻이었어
but it is not confirmed at all.
하지만 전혀 확인된 바는 없습니다.
Yumi, are you getting married? Awesome!
유미 씨, 결혼해요? 엄청난!
This is seriously killing me.
이것은 나를 심각하게 죽이고 있습니다.
Seonbae!
선배!
Oh, Wu Gi!
아, 우기!
Can I ask you just one thing?
하나만 물어봐도 될까요?
I heard some rumors that you're getting marr—
당신이 망가지고 있다는 소문을 들었어요—
I'm not getting married! I'm not. It's just a fake rumor.
나는 결혼하지 않습니다! 나는 그렇지 않습니다. 그냥 가짜 루머일 뿐입니다.
What do you mean marriage? It hasn't been long since we've met.
결혼은 무슨 뜻인가요? 우리가 만난 지 얼마 되지 않았습니다.
Isn't the rumor itself laughable?
소문 자체가 웃기지 않나요?
I really don't know who spread that rumor...
누가 그런 소문을 퍼뜨렸는지 정말 모르겠어요...
I know, right?
나도 알아, 그렇지?
- Huh?
- 뭐?
Really, fake news is going crazy.
정말 가짜뉴스가 난무하고 있습니다.
It's a scary world, right?
무서운 세상이죠?
And this incident became a trauma to Yumi.
그리고 이 사건은 유미에게 트라우마가 됐다.
It's Louis!
루이스예요!
- Hello! - Oh?
- 안녕하세요! - 오?
What's happening?
무슨 일이야?
Hello...
안녕하세요...
Good thing, I was going to buy food for Louis too. Do you want some?
다행이다, 나도 루이를 위한 음식을 사려고 했었다. 좀 드시겠어요?
Yes ... No ... Are you two getting married?
예... 아니... 둘이 결혼하시나요?
You're one step behind.
당신은 한 걸음 뒤처져 있습니다.
I heard you were getting married next spring?
내년 봄에 결혼한다고 들었어?
That was so long ago.
그건 너무 오래 전 일이에요.
I just heard it. I heard it after pooping in the restroom.
방금 들었어. 화장실에서 똥을 싸고 난 후에 그 소리를 들었습니다.
You're a traitor.
당신은 배신자입니다.
I'm going to buy the sandwich.
나는 샌드위치를 ​​사러 갈 거예요.
I'm going to buy you the same thing as mine. This one is really good.
나는 당신에게 나와 같은 것을 사줄 것입니다. 이건 정말 좋아요.
Who told you this?
누가 당신에게 이것을 말했습니까?
May I take your order?
주문을 받아도 될까요?
Yes...Uh...
네...어...
Marriage became a taboo word between the two of them.
결혼은 두 사람 사이에 금기시되는 단어가 됐다.
The aftermath blew up into the cell village as well.
여파는 세포마을에도 터졌다.
I will now make a judgment regarding the Hong Na Ri wedding incident case.
이제 홍나리 결혼사건에 대한 판단을 내리겠습니다.
Defendant, Sensitivity cell.
피고, 민감도 세포.
The Defendant used Reaction #1 without the consent of the cells.
피고는 세포의 동의 없이 반응 #1을 사용했습니다.
She turned Yumi into a liar,
그녀는 유미를 거짓말쟁이로 만들었어
and made Yumi's credibility drop significantly.
유미의 신뢰도를 크게 떨어뜨렸습니다.
Because she almost broke the relationship with Wung
그녀는 Wung과의 관계를 거의 깨뜨릴 뻔했기 때문에
and acted dangerously, she is found guilty.
위험한 행동을 했다는 이유로 유죄 판결을 받았습니다.
Reaction #1 was prohibited indefinitely from being used.
반응 #1은 무기한 사용이 금지되었습니다.
And Sensitivity was in solitary confinement for a month.
그리고 감도는 한 달 동안 독방에 감금되었습니다.
- Sensitivity! - Oh, Reason!
- 민감성! - 오, 이유!
It's tough, right?
힘든 일이죠?
It's bearable.
견딜 수 있습니다.
Why did you do such a thing? I stopped you.
왜 그런 일을 했나요? 나는 당신을 막았습니다.
It's fine. I don't regret it.
괜찮습니다. 나는 그것을 후회하지 않는다.
- What? - I'm sure about Wung this time.
- 무엇? - 이번에는 Wung에 대해 확신합니다.
Reason, could you deliver this for me?
이유야, 이거 좀 배달해줄래?
I will put this on here.
여기에 올려 놓겠습니다.
Bulletin board! Please stick this on.
게시판! 이것을 붙여주세요.
Keep up the good work.
계속 좋은 일을 하세요.
What? Again?
무엇? 다시?
I want to get married with Wung.
나는 웅과 결혼하고 싶다.
Why do so many stories like this keep coming in these days?
요즘 왜 이런 이야기가 계속 많이 나오나요?
- What's that? - I wonder too.
- 그게 뭐죠? -나도 궁금하다.
So, how did that work out?
그래서 그게 어떻게 됐나요?
What do you mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
Did Yumi and Wung end up getting married in Hawaii the following year?
유미와 웡은 결국 이듬해 하와이에서 결혼하게 됐나요?
If you want to know that, you will need to read 33 books of the encyclopedia, right?
그걸 알고 싶으면 백과사전 33권을 읽어야겠죠?
I saw a wedding picture earlier.
예전에 웨딩사진을 봤는데
Really? Of whom?
정말? 누구 중?
Well it was—
글쎄요—
Guys! This incident didn't stop there.
얘들아! 이번 사건은 여기서 끝나지 않았습니다.
It brought about
그 결과
two really important developments in Yumi's life.
유미의 인생에서 정말 중요한 두 가지 발전이 있었습니다.
Your order is here.
주문이 완료되었습니다.
- Thank you! - Enjoy the food.
- 감사합니다! - 음식을 즐겨보세요.
Wung, from tomorrow I'm starting to exercise.
웅, 내일부터 운동 시작해요.
- Exercise? - I told you I was going to do a half-marathon.
- 운동? - 하프마라톤을 하겠다고 했어요.
I have to start training my body now.
이제 몸 단련을 시작해야 합니다.
This delicious overly sweet drink is my last dinner. I need to take care of myself starting from tomorrow.
이 맛있고 지나치게 달콤한 음료가 나의 마지막 저녁 식사입니다. 내일부터 몸관리 좀 해야겠어요.
We might not be able to see each other often because I have to run.
달려야 해서 자주 만나지 못할 수도 있어요.
Don't be too sad and cry.
너무 슬퍼하지 말고 울지 마세요.
Aren't you overdoing it?
너무 과하게 하는거 아냐?
I'm not.
나는 그렇지 않습니다.
One was that she wanted to give an impression of a cool girlfriend who is not focused on marriage,
하나는 결혼에 치중하지 않은 멋진 여자친구의 느낌을 주고 싶었고,
so she started training for a marathon.
그래서 그녀는 마라톤 훈련을 시작했습니다.
Si Yeon, are you looking at this? This is my boyfriend!
시연아, 이거 보고 있어? 이 사람은 내 남자친구야!
I got the bouquet!
꽃다발을 받았어요!
Na Ri, congrats! Have a happy life!
나리님, 축하해요! 행복한 삶을 보내세요!
#I'lldryit #andgiveit #backtoyou.* (Something Korean girls do when they get the bouquet; also means she will take good care of it)
#말려서 #돌려드릴께요.* (한국 여자들이 꽃다발을 받을 때 하는 행동, 또한 그녀가 꽃다발을 잘 돌본다는 뜻이기도 함)
The other one,
다른 하나는
was that it awakened Sae Yi's own heart.
세이 자신의 마음을 일깨웠다는 것이었습니다.
I'm never going to get married!
나는 결코 결혼하지 않을 것입니다!
But if someday I do get married,
하지만 언젠가 결혼하게 된다면
It will probably be to Gu Wung.
아마도 구웅에게 있을 것이다.
But if someday I do get married, it will probably be to Gu Wung.
하지만 언젠가 제가 결혼하게 된다면 아마 구웅과 결혼하게 될 것 같아요.
Wung, I just arrived!
웅, 방금 도착했어요!
Yumi, did you arrive already?
유미 씨, 벌써 도착했어요?
The bus arrived quickly.
버스는 빨리 도착했다.
I'm going out now. It will take me 15 minutes.
나는 지금 나가고있다. 15분 정도 걸릴 거예요.
Take your time coming!
천천히 오세요!
Okay. Just wait for a bit.
좋아요. 조금만 기다리세요.
Sae Yi Wung, are you at home now?
새이 웅, 지금 집에 있나요?
Yes.
예.
I have a favor to ask you.
부탁드릴 게 있어요.
What is it?
그것은 무엇입니까?
Could you lend me a hammer?
망치 좀 빌려 주시겠어요?
A hammer?
망치?
I have some nails to hammer, but I don't have a hammer at home.
망치질할 못은 좀 있는데 집에 망치가 없어요.
Just go to the supermarket and buy one.
그냥 슈퍼마켓에 가서 하나 사세요.
I need it right now. Can I stop by your place?
지금 당장 필요해요. 당신 집에 들러도 될까요?
What is she saying?
그녀가 무슨 말을 하는 걸까요?
You're coming here?
여기로 오시나요?
Yes.
예.
But I have to go out right now.
하지만 지금 당장 나가야 해요.
I'll come right away.
바로 갈게요.
What the heck? She's coming right away?
도대체 뭐야? 그 사람 지금 바로 오나요?
Her house is far from here. Anyway, that's up to her.
그녀의 집은 여기서 멀다. 어쨌든 그것은 그녀에게 달려 있습니다.
Who is it?
누구입니까?
Wung, it's me!
웅, 나야!
Who...?
WHO...?
It's me, Sae Yi!
나야, 세이!
- Huh? - The hammer.
- 뭐? - 망치.
What the heck? You said you were home.
도대체 뭐야? 집에 있다고 했잖아.
- How did you— - I moved in yesterday.
- 어떻게- - 어제 이사했어요.
- What? - You probably didn't hear about it because you were at your parents' house for several days.
- 무엇? - 아마도 며칠 동안 부모님 집에 있었기 때문에 그 소식을 듣지 못했을 것입니다.
Louis knows.
루이스는 알고 있다.
What did you just say?
방금 뭐라고 했어?
I moved here to the 5th floor. Unit 503.
저는 여기 5층으로 이사했어요. 503호.
I thought you knew.
나는 당신이 알고 있다고 생각했습니다.
No wonder, I was sad that you didn't contact me when I moved in.
당연하지, 이사할 때 연락이 없어서 슬펐어.
Let's get along well in the future, good neighbor!
앞으로도 잘 지내자, 좋은 이웃!
The hammer, please.
망치 주세요.
It costs too much to take a taxi back and forth whenever I work overtime.
야근을 할 때마다 택시를 타고 왕복하려면 비용이 너무 많이 든다.
And it's tiring.
그리고 그것은 피곤합니다.
My mom told me to get my own place instead.
엄마는 나에게 대신 내 자리를 구하라고 하셨다.
You told me how it was living in this officetel some months ago.
당신은 몇 달 전 이 오피스텔에 어떻게 살고 있는지 말해줬어요.
I don't think I have ever told you that living here is great.
나는 여기서 사는 것이 좋다는 말을 한 번도 한 적이 없는 것 같아요.
There were no other places like here.
여기만한 곳이 또 없었어요.
It's close to the company and it's clean since it's new.
회사에서 가깝고, 새건물이라 깨끗해요.
Come eat for dinner now and then.
가끔 저녁 먹으러 오세요.
- Dinner? - I always cook my own food.
- 저녁? - 나는 항상 음식을 직접 요리한다.
Don't eat delivery food, if you're hungry come.
배달음식은 먹지 마시고, 배고프면 오세요.
I just have to put another pair of chopsticks on the table.
테이블 위에 젓가락 한 쌍을 더 올려놓으면 돼요.
Here you are.
여기 있어요.
I can bring it back to you tomorrow, right? I have a lot of nails to hammer.
내일 다시 가져다 드릴 수 있겠죠? 망치질할 못이 많아요.
Do as you please.
원하는 대로 하세요.
Ah, that's right! Are you busy now?
아, 그렇구나! 지금 바쁘신가요?
I have plans right now.
지금은 계획이 있어요.
Couldn't you just hammer one nail for me before you go?
가기 전에 못 하나만 망치로 쳐주면 안 될까요?
I have to put a clock on the wall but it's too high.
벽에 시계를 걸어야 하는데 너무 높아요.
You can't?
당신은 할 수 없습니다?
Please do it before you go. Uh?
가기 전에 꼭 해주세요. 음?
Wung!
웅!
You waited a while, right? Sorry.
좀 기다리셨죠? 죄송합니다.
You said it would take you 15 minutes. Turns out it took you 30 minutes, Gu Wung.
15분 정도 걸린다고 하더군요. 알고보니 30분 걸렸네요, Gu Wung.
- Ah... Well. That's because... - Huh?
- 아... 글쎄요. 그 이유는... - 응?
Yumi, you know...
유미, 알잖아...
What?
무엇?
It's nothing.
그것은 아무것도 아니다.
What do you mean "it's nothing?"
"아무것도 아니다"은(는) 무슨 뜻인가요?
No, never mind. Let's go, we'll be late.
아뇨, 신경 쓰지 마세요. 가자, 늦겠다.
What do you mean never mind?
신경 쓰지 마은 무슨 뜻인가요?
That's how the Hong Na Ri incident
홍나리 사건은 이래
led to other important events such as Sae Yi's heart was awakened
세이의 마음이 깨어나는 등 다른 중요한 사건으로 이어졌습니다
and Yumi started training for a marathon.
그리고 유미는 마라톤 훈련을 시작했습니다.
Wow.
우와.
Ma'am. So, Yumi started training for the marathon?
부인. 그럼 유미는 마라톤 훈련을 시작했다는 건가요?
Why is this important?
이것이 왜 중요합니까?
Well, that's...
글쎄요...
Episode 22 Yumi's guards
22화 유미의 경비병
What the heck? It's getting cold already?
도대체 뭐야? 벌써 추워지나요?
♫ I feel like I'm in Paris or anywhere. ♫
♫ 파리나 그 어느 곳에나 있는 것 같은 기분이에요. ♫
♫ Having just woken up from a dream I ♫
♫ 꿈에서 막 깨어난 나는 ♫
♫ Feel like I'm crazy or anyway ♫
♫ 내가 미친 것 같거나 어쨌든 ♫
♫  I'm together with you holding hands ♫
♫ 손을 잡고 함께해요 ♫
♫ like I'm in anywhere ♫
♫ like I'm in anywhere ♫
Ah, I'm tired.
아, 피곤해.
Good morning! Are you up?
좋은 아침이에요! 일어나셨나요?
Of course, I'm currently at the park.
물론, 나는 지금 공원에 있어요.
The park?
공원?
At such a time, why?
그럴 때 왜?
I told you that I would be training for the half-marathon starting from today.
오늘부터 하프마라톤 훈련을 한다고 했는데요.
Ah, that's right. You said so.
아, 그렇군요. 당신은 그렇게 말했어요.
I see that you don't pay attention to your girlfriend haha
여자친구한테 관심을 두지 않는 것 같더라고요 하하
Don't pay attention? I found out what middle school you went to.
주의를 기울이지 않습니까? 네가 어느 중학교에 다녔는지 알아냈어.
Where is it?
어디입니까?
Sport High school.* (T/N : A pun mixing 'middle school' and 'sport' in Korean also means I'm doing exercise right now).
스포츠 고등학교.* (T/N: '중학교'와 '스포츠'를 한국어로 섞은 말장난도 내가 지금 운동을 하고 있다는 뜻입니다).
What the heck.
대체 뭐야?
I know what middle school you went to, too.
당신도 어느 중학교 나왔는지 알아요.
Where is it?
어디입니까?
Love high school.* (T/N: Pun mixing 'middle school' and 'relationship' in Korean also means I'm in a relationship)
고등학교를 사랑하세요.* (T/N: '중학교'와 '연애'를 한국어로 섞으면 연애 중이라는 뜻이기도 합니다.)
Correct!
옳은!
Excuse me, I'm sorry.
죄송합니다. 죄송합니다.
Pardon?
뭐라고요?
Do you know where the park exit is?
공원 출구가 어디인지 아시나요?
If you go that way, you'll find the exit.
그쪽으로 가면 출구가 나옵니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Sorry, someone just asked me for directions.
죄송합니다. 방금 누군가가 길을 물어봤습니다.
A man?
남자?
What a jealous guy.
정말 질투심 많은 사람이에요.
A young man?
젊은 남자?
I don't know I don't remember
모르겠어요 기억이 안 나네요
He's so handsome!
그는 너무 잘생겼어요!
He looks good!
그는 좋아 보인다!
Today's lunch is a new curry restaurant.
오늘 점심은 신개념 카레집입니다.
#goodrestaurantatwork, #mytaste, #goodcurryrestaurant, #curryrice
#goodrestaurantatwork, #mytaste, #goodcurryrestaurant, #curryrice
Eonni, did you see it earlier?
언니, 아까 봤죠?
I saw it! - Saw what?
나는 그것을 보았다! - 뭘 봤어?
The guy who served us when we ate curry.
카레 먹을 때 서빙해주시던 분.
The cutie at the curry place, he was so handsome.
카레집 귀염둥이, 너무 잘생겼어요.
Right? We're going to have to go back tomorrow.
오른쪽? 우리는 내일 다시 돌아가야 할 것 같아요.
Yeah, he's totally super handsome.
응, 그 사람 완전 잘생겼어.
What? Who are you talking about?
무엇? 누구에 대해 이야기하고 있습니까?
That part-timer at the curry place. Our server.
그 카레집 알바. 우리 서버.
The part-timer at the curry place?
카레집 아르바이트?
Who ordered shrimp fry curry?
새우튀김 카레를 주문한 사람은 누구인가요?
Me, me.
나, 나.
I should take pics.
사진을 찍어야겠어요.
Me.
나.
Do you need anything else?
다른 것이 필요합니까?
- We're good. - Enjoy your meal.
- 우린 괜찮아요. - 맛있게 드세요.
- Thank you. - We'll enjoy it.
- 감사합니다. - 우리는 그것을 즐길 것입니다.
- Let's dig in. It looks good.
- 파헤쳐보자. 좋아 보인다.
Right. I guess it was a young guy.
오른쪽. 아무래도 젊은 남자였던 것 같아요.
What? You didn't see him?
무엇? 그 사람 못 봤어?
I don't remember his face.
나는 그의 얼굴을 기억하지 못한다.
How can you not remember that face? It was legendary.
어떻게 그 얼굴을 기억하지 못하나요? 그것은 전설적이었습니다.
I was busy taking pics. You should have told me if he was that handsome.
사진 찍느라 바빴어요. 그 사람이 그렇게 잘생겼다면 나한테 말했어야 했는데.
He came over so many times. He brought water and banchan and stuff.
그는 너무 여러 번 왔습니다. 그는 물과 반찬 등을 가져 왔습니다.
He did?
그랬나요?
Why did I not know?
나는 왜 몰랐을까?
I must have been too busy eating.
아무래도 먹느라 바빴나 봐요.
I was starving since I trained for the marathon this morning.
오늘 아침 마라톤 훈련을 하고 나서 배가 고팠다.
That's not it. It's not because she was too busy eating.
그게 아닙니다. 식사에 너무 바빠서가 아닙니다.
It's because Men Reconnaissance Team is not working these days.
요즘 남자정찰팀이 일을 안해서 그렇습니다.
They always observe everywhere and spy if there are any cute guys,
항상 곳곳을 관찰하며 귀여운 남자가 있는지 감시하고,
Hmm? 5 o'clock. Spotted totally Yumi's style!
흠? 5시. 완전 유미 스타일 발견!
Hmm? Where? Where?
흠? 어디? 어디?
Yumi, to your 5 o'clock. Turn your head.
유미 씨, 5시로 가세요. 고개를 돌리세요.
Sir, please go to Yeonnam-dong.
선생님, 연남동으로 가주세요.
Yumi, on your right! On the right side mirror!
유미 씨 오른쪽이에요! 오른쪽 사이드미러에요!
Their main task is to find guys who are Yumi's style.
그들의 주요 임무는 유미 스타일의 남자를 찾는 것입니다.
Reason, since Yumi's got a boyfriend now, we'll take a short break.
이유는 이제 유미에게 남자친구가 생겼으니 잠시 쉬어가겠습니다.
You won't need us for a while, right?
당분간은 우리가 필요하지 않을 거에요, 그렇죠?
Okay. Then when will you get back?
좋아요. 그럼 언제 돌아올 거예요?
When Yumi gets lonely again.
유미가 또 외로워질 때.
- Have fun! - Aloha!
- 재미있게 보내세요! - 알로하!
Wung!
웅!
Yumi.
유미.
You're early.
일찍 왔네요.
Yumi!
유미!
- Are you okay? - Ow, it hurts.
- 괜찮으세요? - 아, 아파요.
You tend to fall often. Please be more careful.
당신은 자주 넘어지는 경향이 있습니다. 좀 더 주의해주세요.
Why? Does it still hurt?
왜? 아직도 아파요?
Wung, should we order fried chicken?
웅, 프라이드 치킨을 주문할까?
No, maybe pizza might be better.
아니, 어쩌면 피자가 더 나을지도 몰라.
No, let's eat chicken. There is a really good place nearby.
아니, 치킨을 먹자. 근처에 정말 좋은 곳이 있어요.
No, pizza...
아니, 피자...
We can order both chicken and pizza.
치킨과 피자를 모두 주문할 수 있어요.
Wung.
웅.
What now?
지금은 무엇입니까?
My heart just fluttered.
마음이 설레기만 했어요.
Then let's eat chicken and pizza.
그럼 치킨이랑 피자를 먹자.
Did you order something already?
이미 주문하셨나요?
I must have a package.
패키지가 있어야합니다.
A package?
패키지?
Oh, it's matching shirts.
아, 어울리는 셔츠구나.
Yeah, I was looking for workout clothes, then bought them. Thought it'd be nice to wear it together and work out.
네, 운동복을 찾다가 샀어요. 같이 입고 운동하면 좋을 것 같아요.
The yellow one is mine.
노란색은 내 것입니다.
The blue one is yours.
파란색은 당신 것입니다.
Let's see.
어디 보자.
- It's nice. - Right?
- 좋네요. - 오른쪽?
- Try it on. - Now?
- 한번 입어보세요. - 지금?
Yes, so I could see if it fits. If it doesn't, I should return it.
네, 그래서 맞는지 알아보았습니다. 안되면 반품해야겠네요.
Okay.
좋아요.
♫ t's not about something I can understand ♫
♫ 그건 내가 이해할 수 있는 문제가 아니야 ♫
♫ To me who spent a day I couldn't even imagine ♫
♫ 하루를 보낸 나에게는 상상조차 할 수 없었던 ♫
Oh? You have a mole on your back.
오? 등에 점이 있습니다.
On my back? I don't have a mole on my back.
내 등에? 제 등에 점이 없습니다.
You do. Right there.
당신은 그렇습니다. 바로 거기.
Where?
어디?
Here.
여기.
Coming, who is it?
온다, 누구야?
What? Who called me?
무엇? 누가 나한테 전화했어?
Here's the mole.
여기 두더지가 있습니다.
- The chicken... - Hmm?
- 치킨은... - 흠?
Can you order it later?
나중에 주문할 수 있나요?
Should I just order the pizza first?
그냥 피자부터 주문할까요?
No.
아니요.
♫ Sing me a song song song song song♫
♫ 나에게 노래를 불러주세요 노래 노래 노래 노래♫
♫ so that I can feel your love love love love ♫
♫ 너의 사랑을 느낄 수 있게 사랑 사랑 사랑 ♫
♫ In a corner of my heart ♫
♫ 내 마음 한구석에 ♫
♫ I wish someone lives there♫
♫ 누군가 거기에 살았으면 좋겠어요♫
Have fun working out.
즐겁게 운동하세요.
♫ For the many questions, ♫
♫ 많은 질문에 대해서는 ♫
♫ Tell me the answers ♫
♫ 답을 말해주세요 ♫
Let's go!
갑시다!
With no sign of Men Reconnaissance Team's long-term vacation ending,
남자 정찰대 장기 휴가가 끝날 기미가 보이지 않는 가운데,
- Yumi's Guards returned to the village instead. - Let's go
- 대신 유미의 경비병들이 마을로 돌아왔습니다. - 가자
Excuse me!
실례합니다!
What was that? Who is that?
그게 뭐였지? 그 사람은 누구입니까?
Who is it?
누구입니까?
Me?
나?
Yes. Well. I was just wondering.
예. 잘. 그냥 궁금했어요.
Are you Kim Yumi?
김유미요?
Who is it? Do you know them?
누구입니까? 당신은 그들을 알고 있나요?
- No. - You don't know him either?
- 아니. - 너도 그 사람 몰라?
If an unknown man says "excuse me,"
모르는 사람이 "실례합니다"라고 말하면
it's my turn to step up.
이제 내가 올라갈 차례다.
This is an order. Lock the door of her heart immediately and put all cells on high alert.
이것은 명령입니다. 즉시 그녀의 마음의 문을 잠그고 모든 세포를 경계 상태에 두십시오.
Security alert!
보안 경고!
- You never know. He might ask for her number– - Guard!
- 당신은 절대 모르죠. 그는 그녀의 전화번호를 물을지도 모릅니다. - 경비!
- What? - Wait! Wait!
- 무엇? - 기다리다! 기다리다!
Don't do that. Instead, let's see if he is on the list of men you know.
그러지 마세요. 대신, 당신이 아는 남자 목록에 그 사람이 있는지 살펴보자.
Isn't it rude not to recognize someone you already know?
이미 알고 있는 사람을 알아보지 못하는 것은 무례한 일이 아닌가?
That's true. That would be a problem.
그것은 사실이다. 그것은 문제가 될 것입니다.
But. Does Yumi really know that many men?
하지만. 유미는 정말 그렇게 많은 남자를 알고 있나요?
It's not this one.
이건 아니다.
It's this one. The number of men she knows.
바로 이것입니다. 그녀가 아는 남자의 수.
Who?
WHO?
He's not there. He's a face that she doesn't recognize. He's not on the list.
그는 거기에 없습니다. 그 사람은 그녀가 모르는 얼굴이다. 그 사람은 목록에 없어요.
How did you know my name?
내 이름을 어떻게 알았나요?
You are Assistant Manager Kim Yumi, right?
김유미 대리 맞죠?
Hello! I'm Assistant Manager Yu Ba Bi from the marketing department.
안녕하세요! 저는 마케팅부 유바비 대리입니다.
Ah! Yes.
아! 예.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
I saw you a few times and thought you looked familiar, I was right.
몇 번 뵙고 낯익은 줄 알았는데, 맞았어요.
Last time, I even asked you for directions.
지난번에는 길을 물어보기도 했어요.
Did you?
그랬나요?
Um. Yes.
음. 예.
Anyway, it's nice to meet a co-worker living in the same neighborhood.
아무튼 같은 동네에 사는 직장 동료를 만나서 반가워요.
Sure. Sure.
확신하는. 확신하는.
Well, I'll see you next time.
그럼 다음에 뵙겠습니다.
Sure! Goodbye.
확신하는! 안녕히 가세요.
Oh wait! By chance
아 잠깐! 우연히
Yes?
예?
I knew it! You punk. You're busted!
나는 그것을 알고 있었다! 이 새끼야. 당신은 체포됐다!
By chance.
우연히.
By chance what? What?
우연히 뭐? 무엇?
Is it an attempt to get into Yumi's heart? No way! Not as long as I'm here!
유미의 마음에 들어가려는 시도인가? 안 돼요! 내가 여기 있는 한은 안돼!
Look here. I'm sorry but Yumi has a boyfriend!
여기를 보세요. 미안하지만 유미에게는 남자친구가 있어요!
Yes?
예?
Did you lose an umbrella?
우산을 잃어버렸나요?
Excuse me?
실례합니다?
It looks like a fried egg.
계란후라이처럼 생겼네요.
Oh my! That's mine. Fried egg!
이런! 그건 내꺼야 계란후라이!
Yes. It is mine!
예. 내 꺼야!
We found the umbrella!
우리는 우산을 찾았어요!
We found it! It was expensive!
우리가 찾았어요! 비쌌어요!
That's great, Stingy.
정말 좋아요, 스팅지.
Guard! I think you can lower your guns.
경비원! 총을 낮추시면 될 것 같아요.
But I still can't let go of my guard!
하지만 아직도 방심은 놓지 못해요!
He could say something like "I found your umbrella, so please buy me a cup of coffee."
그는 "우산 찾았으니 커피 한잔 사주세요"와 같은 말을 할 수도 있다.
You are busted.
당신은 체포되었습니다.
What is he doing?
그는 무엇을 하고 있나요?
I thought it was gone so I had given up on it!
없어진 줄 알고 포기했어요!
That's such a relief!
정말 다행이네요!
I found it in the company lobby, so it's at the office. I will bring it to the accounting team tomorrow.
회사 로비에서 찾았으니 사무실에 있어요. 내일 회계팀에 가져가겠습니다.
No, you don't have to. I'll go to the marketing department.
아니요, 그럴 필요는 없습니다. 나는 마케팅 부서로 갈 것이다.
Your name was written under the handle.
손잡이 아래에 당신의 이름이 적혀 있었습니다.
Yes! Yes! You're right.
예! 예! 당신 말이 맞아요.
I also didn't notice, but my girlfriend saw it and told me.
저도 눈치채지 못했는데 여자친구가 보고 말해줬어요.
Ah!
아!
He has a girlfriend.
그는 여자 친구가 있습니다.
Hey! Hey! He has a girlfriend. Are you going to continue doing that?
여기요! 여기요! 그는 여자 친구가 있습니다. 계속 그 일을 할 건가요?
If that's the case then- Ow!
그렇다면- 아야!
Security alert cancelled.
보안 경고가 취소되었습니다.
It was an umbrella I really loved.
정말 마음에 들었던 우산이에요.
- Thank you. - Don't mention it.
- 감사합니다. - 언급하지 마세요.
Then, I'll leave it at the lobby information desk.
그럼 로비 안내데스크에 맡기겠습니다.
Hello. Yes. Hello.
안녕하세요. 예. 안녕하세요.
Assistant Manager Yu Babi from the marketing team left an umbrella for me?
마케팅팀 유바비 대리가 우산을 놓고 갔다고?
Ahh. Yes.
아아. 예.
- Are you Assistant Manager Kim Yumi? - Yes, that's me.
- 김유미 대리님이신가요? - 네, 그게 바로 나예요.
Thank you!
감사합니다!
It's really nice to see you.
만나서 정말 반가워요.
Yumi!
유미!
Hi, Yi Da.
안녕하세요, 이다입니다.
Oh? Your umbrella!
오? 당신의 우산!
I found it! I thought I had lost it.
찾았어요! 나는 그것을 잃어버린 줄 알았다.
Where did you find it? I thought you couldn't find it anywhere?
어디서 찾았나요? 어디서도 찾을 수 없을 줄 알았는데?
Someone from marketing left it in the lobby for me.
마케팅 부서의 누군가가 나를 위해 로비에 그것을 두고 왔습니다.
Oh really?
오, 진짜?
That's great!
훌륭해요!
Do you know Assistant Manager Yu Ba Bi in the marketing department?
마케팅부 유바비 대리를 아시나요?
- Yu Ba Bi? - Yes.
- 유바비? - 예.
A man named Yu Ba Bi found it for me.
유바비라는 남자가 찾아줬어요.
I may have seen him a few times here, but I've never seen him before.
나는 그를 여기서 몇 번 본 적이 있지만, 이전에는 한 번도 본 적이 없습니다.
The Assistant Manager Yu Ba Bi who transferred here from the Jeju branch last month?
지난달 제주지사에서 이곳으로 옮긴 유바비 대리요?
He came from Jeju branch. No wonder he looked unfamiliar.
제주지사에서 오셨어요. 그가 낯설게 보였던 것도 당연합니다.
Assistant Manager Yu Ba Bi, who is the second most handsome man of Daehan Noodles, found your umbrella?
대한국수 2위 미남 유바비 대리가 우산을 찾았나요?
Handsome man? That guy?
미남자? 그 사람?
Hey! He is good looking!
여기요! 그는 잘 생겼어요!
Is he? By the way, he lives in my neighborhood.
그 사람인가요? 그런데 그 사람은 우리 동네에 살아요.
What?
무엇?
The second most handsome man in the company found your umbrella
회사에서 두 번째로 잘생긴 남자가 당신의 우산을 찾았어요
and he happens to live, of all places, in your neighborhood too?
그리고 그 사람이 우연히 당신 동네에도 살고 있다고요?
Anyway, I'm really glad he found it. It's a good thing that I wrote my name on it.
어쨌든, 그가 찾아서 정말 다행이에요. 이름을 써서 다행이네요.
Hey, can I touch it just once?
야, 한 번만 만져봐도 돼?
Good morning! Oh! You found your umbrella.
좋은 아침이에요! 오! 당신은 우산을 찾았습니다.
She found it.
그녀는 그것을 찾았습니다.
Hot chocolate
핫 초콜릿
Hello!
안녕하세요!
Did you get your umbrella?
우산은 챙기셨나요?
Yes.
예.
Oh! It's the savior who found our prized umbrella!
오! 우리의 소중한 우산을 찾아주신 분이 구세주이십니다!
Should we get the savior a cup of hot cocoa?
구세주에게 뜨거운 코코아 한 잔을 드려야 할까요?
Yumi doesn't have any change, I'll have to break a thousand won bill.
유미는 잔돈이 없어서 천원짜리를 깨뜨려야 할 것 같다.
You just called him a savior!
당신은 방금 그를 구세주라고 불렀습니다!
Would you like some? It's hot chocolate.
좀 드시겠어요? 핫초코예요.
Ah. Thank you.
아. 감사합니다.
The weather is cold today.
오늘은 날씨가 춥습니다.
It is.
그것은.
You haven't worked out at night for a few days, right? I don't think I've seen you.
며칠 동안 밤에 운동을 안 하신 거죠? 내 생각에는 당신을 본 적이 없는 것 같아요.
I only come out when my boyfriend is busy.
저는 남자친구가 바쁠 때만 나옵니다.
Me too. Because I don't have anything to do when I'm not meeting my girlfriend.
저도요. 왜냐하면 여자친구를 만나지 않으면 할 일이 없거든요.
I see.
알겠어요.
She's a reporter, but she must be very busy these days.
기자인데 요즘 많이 바쁠 것 같아요.
So these days, I work out on the weekend too.
그래서 요즘은 주말에도 운동을 해요.
I see.
알겠어요.
It's good to come in the morning on the weekend. There are too many people in the afternoon.
주말에는 아침에 오는 것이 좋습니다. 오후에는 사람이 너무 많습니다.
I always come in the mornings on the weekends.
주말에는 항상 아침에 옵니다.
I see.
알겠어요.
Are you done? Give it to me, I'll throw it away on my way.
끝났나요? 나한테 줘, 가는 길에 버릴게.
It's okay.
괜찮아요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
I'll see you later. Thanks for the drink.
나중에 뵙겠습니다. 음료 주셔서 감사합니다.
Sure. Enjoy your workout.
확신하는. 운동을 즐겨보세요.
We met Yu Ba Bi at the park again today.
오늘도 공원에서 유바비를 만났습니다.
The conversation was nothing special.
대화 내용은 특별한 것이 없었습니다.
It was a conversation to not feel awkward while drinking hot chocolate.
핫초코를 마시면서 어색함을 느끼지 않기 위한 대화였다.
But this part is bothering me a bit.
그런데 이 부분이 좀 마음에 걸리네요.
It's good to come in the morning on the weekends. There are too many people in the afternoon.
주말에는 아침에 오는 것이 좋습니다. 오후에는 사람이 너무 많습니다.
I always come in the mornings on the weekends.
주말에는 항상 아침에 옵니다.
Is there a good reason for sharing his schedule?
그의 일정을 공유하는 데에는 타당한 이유가 있나요?
Is it just a friendly tip as a neighbor?
그저 이웃으로서 친절한 제보일까요?
Or did he want to tell you about his weekend workout schedule?
아니면 주말 운동 일정을 알려주고 싶었던 걸까요?
Is this an ulterior motive or not?
이것이 은밀한 동기인가 아닌가?
I can't decide if I should defend or not.
방어해야 할지 말아야 할지 결정할 수가 없어요.
Hello!
안녕하세요!
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Assistant Manager Yumi, you're working on the weekend too.
유미대리님, 주말에도 일하시네요.
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
The sky is so beautiful.
하늘이 너무 아름답습니다.
The sky is really clear today.
오늘 하늘이 정말 맑네요.
Yes, it's totally an autumn sky.
네, 완전 가을하늘이에요.
Your hairstyle has changed.
헤어스타일이 바뀌었어요.
It's pretty.
예쁘네요.
Episode 23 : Male Friend, Female Friend?
23화 : 남자친구, 여자친구?
About Yu Ba Bi.
유바비에 대해서.
I think...
내 생각엔...
No. I should wake Yumi Guards. I don't feel good about this.
아뇨. 유미 경비병을 깨워야겠어요. 기분이 좋지 않아요.
Guard! Wake up!
경비원! 깨우다!
We met Yu Ba Bi on our way to work.
출근길에 유바비를 만났습니다.
What? That jerk again!
무엇? 또 그 멍청이!
Your hairstyle changed.
헤어스타일이 바뀌었어요.
It's pretty.
예쁘네요.
I knew this would happen, that jerk!
이런 일이 일어날 줄 알았어, 그 멍청아!
You're going to attack while I'm asleep? Not a chance.
내가 자고 있는 동안 공격할 셈인가? 기회가 아닙니다.
Yumi Guards, this is an order!
유미경비대, 명령이다!
Lock the door to heart and be alert!
마음의 문을 잠그고 깨어 있으십시오!
Again?
다시?
Excuse me?
실례합니다?
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
What did you just say?
방금 뭐라고 했어?
How is my outfit today?
오늘 내 옷 어때요?
- Your outfit? - Yes, it's new.
- 옷이요? - 네, 새로운 거예요.
I think it looks good on you.
내 생각에는 당신에게 잘 어울리는 것 같아요.
Thank you. Your hair is pretty today, too.
감사합니다. 오늘도 머리가 예쁘네요.
I'll get going first.
나 먼저 갈게.
Wait, wait. What was that? He's leaving.
잠깐만요. 그게 뭐였지? 그는 떠난다.
I guess it was just a compliment without any meaning.
그냥 아무 의미도 없는 칭찬이었던 것 같아요.
Yu Ba Bi, that jerk, is making me uncomfortable.
그 멍청이 유바비가 나를 불편하게 만든다.
It's so confusing! How can you tell if he has an ulterior motive or not?
너무 혼란스러워요! 그 사람에게 숨은 동기가 있는지 없는지 어떻게 알 수 있나요?
Idiot. Should I tell you how?
바보. 방법을 알려줘야 할까요?
Detective, can you tell the difference?
형사님, 차이점을 알 수 있나요?
Of course!
물론!
It's simple. Think of Yu Ba Bi as a woman.
간단합니다. 유바비를 여자로 생각해보세요.
- A woman? - Then won't we be able to see his actions more objectively?
- 여자요? -그렇다면 좀 더 객관적으로 그의 행동을 볼 수 있지 않을까요?
By chance...
우연히...
Yes?
예?
Did you lose an umbrella?
우산을 잃어버렸나요?
- Excuse me? - It looks like a fried egg. - Oh, my!
- 실례합니다? - 계란후라이처럼 생겼어요. - 아, 이런!
That's mine. A fried egg. That is mine!
그건 내꺼야 달걀 프라이입니다. 그건 내꺼야!
Right?
오른쪽?
It's better to come in the mornings on weekends. There are a lot of people in the afternoon.
주말에는 아침에 오는 것이 더 좋습니다. 오후에는 사람이 많습니다.
I always come in the mornings on weekends.
주말에는 항상 아침에 옵니다.
I see.
알겠어요.
Yes, it's totally an autumn sky.
네, 완전 가을하늘이에요.
Your hairstyle changed.
헤어스타일이 바뀌었어요.
It's so pretty.
너무 예뻐요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Looks like he just wants to be close.
그 사람은 그냥 가까이 있고 싶어하는 것 같군요.
You're right. It doesn't seem weird when you look at it this way?
당신 말이 맞아요. 이렇게 보면 이상하지 않나요?
- Wait! - Huh?
- 기다리다! - 뭐?
If you put it that way, Seo Sae Yi's actions aren't bad either.
그렇게 따지면 서세이의 행동도 나쁘지 않은 것 같다.
That's not acceptable but this is?
그건 받아들일 수 없지만 이건가?
Wung, a present.
웅, 선물이에요.
It's yuja tea.
유자차 입니다.
I made it myself. You said you got a cold.
내가 직접 만들었어요. 감기에 걸렸다고 하셨어요.
Drink it in the morning and evening. I'm sure you'll get much better.
아침저녁으로 마신다. 나는 당신이 훨씬 나아질 것이라고 확신합니다.
Wung, let's get this one for Yumi.
웅, 유미에게 이걸 사주자.
Don't you think it'll look good on her?
그 사람한테 잘 어울릴 것 같지 않아?
You think?
당신 생각에는?
Oh my.
아, 이런.
You have something on you.
당신에게는 뭔가가 있습니다.
- No! - That's not right.
- 아니요! - 그건 옳지 않아요.
Wung, do you think my way of thinking is a bit old-fashioned?
웅, 내 사고방식이 좀 구식이라고 생각하시나요?
Yeah.
응.
Come on, answer me seriously.
자, 진지하게 대답해 보세요.
Seriously?
진지하게?
Yes.
예.
Gosh.
이런.
Why are you asking all of a sudden?
갑자기 왜 물어보시나요?
It's just I thought I was a bit conservative when it comes to relationships between women and men.
단지 제가 여자와 남자의 관계에 있어서 좀 보수적이라고 생각했을 뿐이에요.
I'm talking about men and women being friends.
나는 남자와 여자가 ​​친구가 되는 것에 대해 이야기하고 있습니다.
Not sure. I guess you are a little more cautious.
확실하지 않습니다. 좀 더 조심스러워지신 것 같아요.
Really? Am I weird?
정말? 내가 이상한가?
- Are you going to be done late again today? - Yeah.
- 오늘 또 늦게 끝날 거예요? - 응.
I think it'd be hard for me to get done early till the end of this month.
이번 달 말까지는 일찍 끝내기가 힘들 것 같아요.
I'll be alone this weekend again.
이번 주말에도 또 혼자 있겠네요.
Just like last weekend.
지난 주말과 마찬가지로요.
Sorry. I'll make sure to finish by this month no matter what.
죄송합니다. 무슨 일이 있어도 이번 달까지는 꼭 끝내겠습니다.
Okay. Don't work too hard.
좋아요. 너무 열심히 일하지 마세요.
- Fighting!
- 화이팅!
What should I do today?
오늘은 무엇을 해야 할까요?
Cabbage.
양배추.
Oh right, I'm out of sugar.
아 맞다, 설탕이 떨어졌어.
Aren't you working out today?
오늘은 운동 안 하시나요?
What are you doing here?
여기서 뭐하는거야?
- What would I be doing? I came to the market to grocery shop. - Right.
- 내가 뭘 하고 있는 거지? 나는 식료품 가게에 시장에 왔습니다. - 오른쪽.
I guess you and I have similar paths, right?
아무래도 당신과 나는 비슷한 길을 걷고 있는 것 같죠?
Is that right?
그렇죠?
You must be making fish cutlets.
생선 커틀릿을 만들고 계실 겁니다.
Yes, my girlfriend is coming over later.
네, 제 여자친구가 나중에 올 거예요.
She likes fish cutlets.
그녀는 생선까스를 좋아해요.
I see.
알겠어요.
Do you know where the tartar sauce is?
타르타르 소스가 어디에 있는지 아시나요?
Tartar sauce...
타르타르 소스...
Are you buying it? It's better homemade.
당신은 그것을 구입하고 있습니까? 집에서 만든 것이 더 좋습니다.
Isn't it hard to make?
만들기 어렵지 않나요?
Not at all. Do you have mayo at home?
별말씀을요. 집에 마요네즈 있어요?
Yes.
예.
You add finely chopped onion and pickle to that.
거기에 잘게 다진 양파와 피클을 추가합니다.
Chop chop chop, very finely.
찹찹 찹찹, 아주 잘게 썰어주세요.
Finely chop onion and pickle?
양파와 피클을 잘게 다져주세요?
Yes, then mix in a boiled egg.
네, 그럼 삶은 달걀을 섞으세요.
Grind the yolk through a sieve.
체를 통해 노른자를 갈아주세요.
Hold on. You're too fast.
기다리다. 당신은 너무 빠릅니다.
Like this?
이와 같이?
Yes, then mix in the boiled egg.
네, 그럼 삶은 계란을 섞어주세요.
- Mix. - Right.
- 믹스. - 오른쪽.
Grind the yolk through a sieve.
체를 통해 노른자를 갈아주세요.
Sensitivity, now that I think of it,
민감성, 이제 생각해보니,
I think men and women can be friends if done correctly.
남자와 여자는 제대로만 하면 친구가 될 수 있다고 생각해요.
Then are you saying you accept Sae Yi?
그럼 세이를 받아들인다는 겁니까?
If you accept male friends, then shouldn't you also accept female friends, too?
남자친구를 받아들이면 여자친구도 받아들여야 하지 않나요?
I cannot accept it.
나는 그것을 받아들일 수 없다.
I don't like stuff like male friends or female friends.
저는 남자친구나 여자친구 같은 걸 별로 안 좋아해요.
What did else you say to put in earlier? Lemon juice?
아까 또 뭘 넣으라고 했어? 레몬 주스?
Yes, one tablespoon of lemon juice.
네, 레몬즙 한 스푼.
There she goes again.
그녀는 또 간다.
- Excuse me for a sec. - Sure.
- 잠시만 실례하겠습니다. - 확신하는.
Yeah, it's me.
응, 나야.
Then you can't come over today?
그럼 오늘은 못 와?
Where else would I be? I'm grocery shopping.
내가 또 어디에 있겠는가? 나는 식료품을 쇼핑하고 있어요.
Then why did you...
그럼 왜...
Never mind. We'll eat it next time.
괜찮아요. 다음에 먹어보겠습니다.
It's fine. You must be busy. You should go back.
괜찮습니다. 바쁘시겠어요. 돌아가야 해.
Okay.
좋아요.
She said she can't come all of a sudden.
갑자기 못 오겠다고 하더군요.
Your girlfriend must be pretty busy.
당신의 여자친구는 꽤 바쁠 것 같아요.
I'm definitely in a relationship but strangely, it seems like I'm more bored now than when I wasn't in a relationship.
분명 연애 중인데 이상하게 연애 안 할 때보다 지금이 더 심심한 것 같아요.
Then see you at work.
그럼 직장에서 봐요.
Enjoy your dinner.
저녁 식사를 즐기십시오.
Sure, good bye.
물론이죠. 안녕히 계세요.
I think I know how that feels.
그 기분이 어떤지 알 것 같아요.
That lonely feeling from time to time even though you're in a relationship.
연애 중인데도 가끔씩 느끼는 외로움.
He must be really busy.
그 사람 정말 바쁜가 보다.
Thank you for the food.
음식을 주셔서 감사합니다.
It's yummy, yummy.
맛있어요, 맛있어요.
So yummy.
정말 맛있어요.
I miss Wung.
웅이 그리워요.
Yumi, are you sleeping?
유미야, 자고 있어?
No, I'm not sleeping.
아니요, 안 자고 있어요.
I'm on my way home.
집에 가는 중이에요.
You got done earlier than I thought.
생각보다 일찍 끝내셨네요.
Yeah. What did you do today?
응. 오늘은 무엇을 했나요?
I made tteokbokki at home, ate, then cleaned up...
집에서 떡볶이를 만들어 먹고, 청소를 ​​하고...
Guys.
얘들아.
Should we surprise Wung?
Wung을 놀라게 해야 할까요?
How?
어떻게?
He wouldn't think that Yumi would come over at this hour.
그는 유미가 이 시간에 올 것이라고는 생각하지 않았을 것이다.
That's a good idea. Wow, I like things like this.
좋은 생각이에요. 와, 저는 이런 걸 좋아해요.
Let's go. Let's go and eat a late night snack together!
갑시다. 같이 야식 먹으러 가자!
Let's text Wung that we're going to sleep now, so he'll be surprised.
이제 자러 간다고 Wung에게 문자를 보내자 그가 놀랄 것이다.
You must be tired. Go to bed.
피곤하겠네요. 잠자리에 드세요.
I should go to bed, too.
나도 자러 가야겠다.
Okay. Good night.
좋아요. 안녕히 주무세요.
Dream about me.
나에 대한 꿈을 꾸세요.
Okay, I'll try haha.
알았어, 해볼게 하하.
If we show up after this, he'll be surprised, right?
이 다음에 우리가 나타나면 그 사람도 놀랄 것 같죠?
Let's go guys, to see Wung!
얘들아, 웡을 만나러 가자!
Let's go see Wung!
웅을 만나러 가자!
No!
아니요!
She's already all washed up and you want to go out?
그녀는 이미 다 씻어냈는데 나가고 싶어?
On top of that, I was just about to put a face mask on!
게다가 마스크도 막 쓰려고 했는데요!
Don't worry. We can take two masks and do it together.
괜찮아요. 마스크 두 개를 가지고 함께 할 수 있어요.
You're a genius!
당신은 천재입니다!
♫ Are you paying attention to me? ♫
♫ 나에게 관심을 기울이고 있나요? ♫
We should do this together.
우리는 이것을 함께 해야 합니다.
Wung's skin was pretty damaged lately.
최근 웅의 피부가 꽤 손상됐어요.
Yay, head to Wung's place with face masks!
예, 마스크를 쓰고 Wung의 집으로 가세요!
Hold on!
기다리다!
It's Monday tomorrow. What about work clothes?
내일은 월요일이에요. 작업복은 어떻습니까?
Don't tell me you're thinking about going to work in what she's wearing now!
그녀가 지금 입고 있는 옷을 입고 출근할 생각이라고 말하지 마세요!
No worries. We can bring what she'll wear tomorrow.
걱정 마세요. 내일 그녀가 입을 옷을 가져오면 돼요.
- There you go. - Aha!
- 됐어요. - 아하!
I should pack clothes for tomorrow.
내일 입을 옷을 챙겨야 해요.
♫ I really want to know how you feel ♫
♫ 당신의 기분이 어떤지 정말 알고 싶어요 ♫
♫  What is obvious♫
♫ 무엇이 명백한가♫
♫ while looking again at me today ♫
♫ 오늘도 나를 바라보며 ♫
♫ You are smiling♫
♫ 당신은 웃고 있어요♫
♫  Although there aren't enough clues♫
♫ 단서가 충분하지는 않지만♫
♫ I have my hunch that ♫
♫ 내 예감은 ♫
♫ I care about you. ♫
♫ 나는 당신을 걱정해요. ♫
Let's go!
갑시다!
♫ I'm getting closer and closer to you ♫
♫ 나는 당신에게 점점 더 가까워지고 있어요 ♫
Thank you.
감사합니다.
♫ Close to you ♫
♫ 당신 가까이에 ♫
♫ I can't hide my feeling for you which is growing bigger and bigger ♫
♫ 점점 커져가는 너를 향한 마음을 감출 수가 없어 ♫
Gu Wung will be so surprised today. ♫ I think it's time♫
오늘은 구웅이가 너무 놀랐을 것 같아요. ♫ 이제 때가 된 것 같아요♫
♫ Close to you ♫
♫ 당신 가까이에 ♫
How should we tease him? Should we hide after we ring the bell?
어떻게 그를 놀려야 할까요? 벨을 누른 후 숨어야 할까요?
♫ I really want to know how you feel♫
♫ 네 기분이 어떤지 정말 알고 싶어♫
♫  What is obvious ♫
♫ 무엇이 명백한가 ♫
♫While looking at me today again, you are smiling ♫
♫오늘도 나를 보며 웃고 있구나 ♫
Should we text 'ding dong' in front of the door?
문 앞에서 '딩동'이라고 문자 보내볼까?
♫ I have my hunch that ♫
♫ 내 예감은 ♫
♫ I care about you.
♫ 나는 당신을 걱정해요.
♫ I want to know how you feel ♫
♫ 네 기분이 어떤지 알고 싶어 ♫
It would be worth seeing his expression.
그의 표정을 볼 가치가 있을 것이다.
I can't wait to see Wung.
빨리 Wung을 만나고 싶어요.
Fifth floor.
5층.
It's Sae Yi!
세이입니다!
Oh, Yumi. Hello.
아, 유미. 안녕하세요.
Sae Yi...
새이...
Wait. What is this? Why is Sae Yi here?
기다리다. 이게 뭔가요? 세이가 왜 여기 있어?
She got on from the fifth floor. Why?
그녀는 5층에서 탔다. 왜?
You must be going to Wung's place.
당신은 Wung의 집으로 가야만 합니다.
So why are you here?
그럼 당신은 왜 여기에 있나요?
I live here.
나는 여기에 산다.
Didn't you know?
몰랐나요?
I moved here on the fifth floor last month.
지난달에 여기 5층으로 이사했어요.
- Sorry? - Gosh.
- 죄송합니다? - 이런.
Wung must've not told you.
Wung이 당신에게 말하지 않았나봐요.
Well, it's nothing he needs to bring up.
글쎄요, 그 사람이 언급할 필요는 없어요.
I'm going to Wung's, too. I need to borrow something.
나도 Wung네 집에 갈 거야. 뭔가를 빌려야 해요.
What is this? What is going on now?
이게 뭔가요? 지금 무슨 일이 일어나고 있나요?
Sae Yi lives here?
세이가 여기에 살아요?
Wung never told us.
Wung은 우리에게 말한 적이 없습니다.
I'll go find out.
제가 가서 알아보겠습니다.
What are you talking about?
무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요?
Sensitivity, don't tell me ... did you escape from prison?
민감성, 말하지 마세요 ... 감옥에서 탈출하셨나요?
Why does Sae Yi live here? Since when? What is this?
세이는 왜 여기에 살아요? 언제부터요? 이게 뭔가요?
What have you guys been doing while I was in jail?
내가 감옥에 있는 동안 너희들은 무엇을 하고 있었나요?
Tenth floor.
10층.
Aren't you getting off?
안 내리나요?
What are you doing, Yumi? You've got to say something back!
뭐하는 거야, 유미? 당신은 뭔가 다시 말해야 해요!
Why are you mute?
왜 벙어리야?
Where is Reaction #1?
반응 #1은 어디에 있나요?
It's been prohibited because of you.
너 때문에 금지됐어
My goodness!
이럴 수가!
It's my first time living on my own, so there are many things I don't have.
처음으로 혼자 생활하다보니 없는 게 너무 많아요.
I'm borrowing things from Wung.
나는 Wung에게서 물건을 빌리고 있습니다.
It's so nice to have a friend as your neighbor, right?
친구가 이웃이라는 건 참 좋은 일이겠죠?
Should I ring?
전화해야 하나?
Sure.
확신하는.
You should at least buy your own wine glasses.
최소한 자신만의 와인잔을 구입해야 합니다.
Yumi.
유미.
We met in the elevator.
우리는 엘리베이터에서 만났습니다.
She didn't know that I moved.
그녀는 내가 이사했다는 것을 몰랐습니다.
I used it well.
잘 사용했어요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
My friend called and said she's bringing wine.
친구가 전화해서 와인을 가져오겠다고 하더군요.
I didn't have any glasses, so I asked for help since it was urgent.
안경이 없어서 급해서 도움을 요청했어요.
- I'll make good use of them. - Sure.
- 잘 활용하겠습니다. - 확신하는.
See you later, Yumi.
나중에 봐, 유미.
Good bye.
안녕히 가세요.
Oh right.
아 맞다.
Yumi, I'm planning a house warming party. Please come.
유미 씨, 집들이 파티를 계획 중이에요. 꼭 오세요.
Sure, invite me.
물론이죠. 초대해 주세요.
I'll come.
내가 갈게.
Then have a good time.
그럼 즐거운 시간 보내세요.
Good night.
안녕히 주무세요.
Yumi.
유미.
How are you here all of a sudden? You said you were going to bed.
갑자기 여기 어떻게 오셨나요? 당신은 잠자리에 든다고 말했습니다.
Come in.
들어오세요.
Come in, Yumi.
들어오세요, 유미님.
♫ I am right here ♫
♫ 나는 바로 여기에 ♫
♫ I haven't changed ♫
♫ 난 변하지 않았어 ♫
What did I say? Male friend? Female friend? Yeah right!
내가 뭐라고 말했나요? 남자 친구? 여자친구? 응 맞아!
There is no such a thing. I was right!
그런 것은 없습니다. 내가 옳았어!
Sensitivity, please be quiet.
민감하신 분은 조용히 해주세요.
You're a fugitive. Why are you so loud?
당신은 도망자입니다. 왜 그렇게 시끄러워요?
I am just so mad! I trusted Wung.
난 정말 화가 났어요! 나는 웅을 믿었다.
I was certain!
나는 확신했다!
♫ As you always run away ♫
♫ 언제나처럼 도망치듯 ♫
♫ while walking at dawn stop,
♫ 새벽 정류장을 걷는 동안,
Yumi.
유미.
♫ wherever  ♫
♫ 어디든지 ♫
♫ your toes touch ♫
♫ 발가락이 닿아요 ♫
♫ Along with dreams, waves and sand ♫
♫ 꿈과 파도와 모래와 함께 ♫
♫ every day I am broken and scattered ♫
♫ 매일 나는 부서지고 흩어진다 ♫
♫ An insignificant romance, my own festival ♫
♫ 사소한 낭만, 나만의 축제 ♫
♫ Oh love, ♫
♫ 오, 사랑해요 ♫
♫ This love which fills a small fist. ♫
♫ 작은 주먹 하나를 채우는 이 사랑. ♫
♫ To make you happy ♫
♫ 당신을 행복하게 해주기 위해 ♫
Yumi's Cells Previe
유미의 세포들 미리보기
She's acting like your girlfriend pretending to be your friend.
그녀는 당신의 친구인 척하는 당신의 여자친구처럼 행동하고 있습니다.
No!
아니요!
I'm worried that you're not happy dating but only getting stressed out.
연애가 행복하지 않고 스트레스만 받는 건 아닌지 걱정이 됩니다.
No, no. Pull yourself together, Wung!
아니, 아니. 힘을 모아, 웡!
We used to have a very special relationship.
우리는 아주 특별한 관계를 갖고 있었습니다.
I don't have any kind of ability to get rid Seo Sae Yi.
나는 서세이를 없앨 능력이 전혀 없다.
But it's my choice to not see him if I don't want to or to keep seeing him if I want to.
하지만 내가 원하지 않으면 그 사람을 보지 않고, 보고 싶으면 계속 만나는 것은 나의 선택입니다.
From now on, Yumi will carry breakup card.
이제부터 유미는 이별 카드를 들고 다닐 예정이다.
Right, I had something to ask you. What are you doing on Christmas?
그렇군요, 물어볼 게 있었습니다. 크리스마스에 뭐해요?